

CONTACT ME AT

- vinicius.mesquita@coppe.ufrj.br
- mesquita.github.io
- in @mesquitavinicius
- @mesquita

SKILLS SUMMARY 🌘



- Programming Languages
 - Python, MATLAB, C++, C
- Machine Learning and Deep Learning
 - Tensorflow, PyTorch, Scikit Learn
- Tools
 - Docker, Git, GitHub, GNU Radio, LaTex

LANGUAGES 🖘

- Portuguese, mother tongue.
- English, advanced.

VINICIUS MESQUITA DE PINHO

ELECTRONIC AND COMPUTER ENGINEER

PERSONAL PROFILE

 Vinicius Mesquita de Pinho received his B.Sc. degree in Electronics and Computing Engineering from the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro (UFRJ), Brazil, in 2019. He is an M.Sc. student in the Electrical Engineering Program -COPPE/UFRJ. Since 2015, he has been working at the Laboratory of Signals, Multimedia, and Telecommunications (SMT).

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

Federal University of Rio de Janeiro

M.Sc. Electrical Engineering | Mar 2019 - Feb 2021

 Master Thesis: "Vision-Aided Radio: User Identity Match in Radio and Video Domains Using Machine Learning"

B.Sc. Electronic and Computer Eng. | Feb 2014 - Feb 2019

 Undergraduate Thesis: "On Equalization Performance in Underwater Acoustic Communication System"

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Intern

Nokia Bell Labs France | Feb 2020 - July 2020

- Six-month internship about leveraging the power of machine learning for computer vision to the optimization of radio networks for future communication generations.
- Journal paper "Vision-Aided Radio: User Identity Match in Radio and Video Domains Using Machine Learning" published in IEEE Access special edition on Beyond 5G Communications.
- A patent application with the methodology developed was filed on the Finnish Patent and Registration Office on Aug 20.

Research Engineer

SMT/COPPE/UFRJ and Petrobras | Aug 2018 - Mar 2020

- Worked as a research engineer exploring solutions using big data and machine learning, successfully identifying and classifying problems in signals acquired during oil well drilling processes.
- Leadership position in the group composed of twelve students, delegating tasks, and managing deliveries.